<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-12-05T04:55:24+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Expedient</title><subtitle>Expedient</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Key Takeaways from KubeCon 2019</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-26-key-takeaways-from-kubecon-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Key Takeaways from KubeCon 2019" /><published>2019-11-26T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-26T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/key-takeaways-from-kubecon-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-26-key-takeaways-from-kubecon-2019/">&lt;p&gt;I recently attended &lt;a href=&quot;https://events19.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-north-america-2019/&quot;&gt;KubeCon + CloudNativeCan North America 2019&lt;/a&gt; in San Diego. The four-day conference was filled with keynotes, breakout sessions, and networking events focused around all things cloud native. Here are my key takeaways from the show:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;security-is-an-unsolved-problem&quot;&gt;Security is an unsolved problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were tons of security vendors at the show with a lot of overlap between products in the image scanning, runtime security, and network policy spaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Everyone’s approaches are slightly different and determining pros/cons of different approaches is not easy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legacy vendors are beginning to release Kubernetes-focused products and purchase/integrate offerings from various new players. A good example of this trend is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paloaltonetworks.com/company/press/2019/palo-alto-networks-completes-acquisition-of-twistlock&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palo Alto Networks’&lt;/strong&gt; acquisition&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;strong&gt;Twistlock&lt;/strong&gt; to extend its Prisma™ cloud security strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The industry is beginning to standardize on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openpolicyagent.org/&quot;&gt;open policy agent&lt;/a&gt; for creating advanced security rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multi-cloud-is-becoming-mature&quot;&gt;Multi-cloud is becoming mature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There were several vendors offering a multi-cloud Kubernetes (k8s) solution with varying degrees of sophistication&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VMWare&lt;/strong&gt; has made a large bet here &lt;a href=&quot;https://blogs.vmware.com/cloudnative/2019/08/26/vmware-completes-approach-to-modern-applications/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;with Tanzu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, but many of the existing vendors here are proving to be stiff competition (especially &lt;strong&gt;Rancher&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most of these solutions are still relying on the managed offerings from the hyperscale clouds but some are beginning to move toward using plain VMs to avoid having different feature sets across different platforms. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;*This trend aligns with Expedient’s vision of providing a seamless cloud infrastructure experience to clients regardless of underlying platform.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;true-cloud-native-requires-the-data-to-be-in-k8s&quot;&gt;True cloud native requires the data to be in k8s&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More vendors and thought leaders are talking about how gaining the full benefits of k8s requires bringing persistent data, and databases in particular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/blog/2019-08-13-persistent-volume-options-for-kubernetes-storage/&quot;&gt;inside of the k8s cluster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This ties in very well with the multi-cloud theme as customers look to remove any lock-in to a specific providers platform by avoiding services like Amazon’s Relational Database Service (RDS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing this data at scale is still a challenge and we’ll likely see a lot of progress made on that problem over the next year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;docker-alternatives-are-starting-to-gain-steam&quot;&gt;Docker alternatives are starting to gain steam&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many people were talking about the recent acquisition of &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2019/11/13/mirantis-acquires-docker-enterprise/&quot;&gt;Docker Enterprise by Mirantis&lt;/a&gt; and what it means for the ecosystem long-term&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The move away from &lt;strong&gt;Docker&lt;/strong&gt; as a container engine and on to projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cri-o.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cri-o&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://containerd.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;containerd&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; was already happening but is likely to accelerate now that docker is no longer in charge of engine development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-one-has-things-figured-out-completely-yet&quot;&gt;No one has things figured out completely yet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even the companies that are farthest along in their container adoption were talking about ongoing efforts to move legacy workloads to k8s&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are still plenty of companies that are just starting their cloud native journey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;kubernetes-itself-is-largely-mature&quot;&gt;Kubernetes itself is largely mature&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There was relatively little talk about k8s itself or new features coming in the next version&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most discussion was on the ecosystem of products that exist around k8s (service mesh, security, image registries, message queuing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning more about k8s, containers, or cloud native? Check out the webinar that we recently hosted with 451 Research. During the webinar, the presenters discussed enterprise adoption of cloud native approaches, the common challenges businesses face during cloud native adoption, and two cloud native case studies featuring Expedient clients. Watch the full webinar replay here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-full h-full sm:w-7/12 video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rvB-Lc2B5BQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mike Garuccio is a Product Strategy Engineer at Expedient focused on researching new software and hardware to find ways to productize this technology into new solutions for Expedient clients. As a ‘full stack’ engineer, Mike works with all layers of infrastructure architecture - from the hypervisor all the way up to front-end applications. Mike has played a leading role in the deployment and implementation of Expedient’s next-generation cloud platform, Expedient Enterprise Cloud. His professional interests include automation, containers, Kubernetes, CI/CD, and developer experience optimization. Follow Mike on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mgaruccio&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mike Garuccio</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">I recently attended KubeCon + CloudNativeCan North America 2019 in San Diego. The four-day conference was filled with keynotes, breakout sessions, and networking events focused around all things cloud native. Here are my key takeaways from the show:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="" /></entry><entry><title type="html">451 Research: Expedient Enterprise Cloud positioned as a stepping stone from the old world to the new</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-25-451-research-expedient-enterprise-cloud-positioned-as-a-stepping-stone-from-the-old-world-to-the-new/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="451 Research: Expedient Enterprise Cloud positioned as a stepping stone from the old world to the new" /><published>2019-11-25T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-25T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/451-research-expedient-enterprise-cloud-positioned-as-a-stepping-stone-from-the-old-world-to-the-new</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-25-451-research-expedient-enterprise-cloud-positioned-as-a-stepping-stone-from-the-old-world-to-the-new/">&lt;p&gt;Shortly after we announced Expedient Enterprise Cloud (EEC) at VMworld 2018, 451 Research published its initial &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/resources/451-research-expedient-launches-enterprise-cloud/&quot;&gt;Market Insight report&lt;/a&gt; on the groundbreaking cloud, which noted that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Companies like Expedient are at the coal face of enterprise and cloud right now, and pulling out the rewards therein. Early recognition of where the trends were headed and adoption of key new technology like NSX have allowed Expedient to be innovative on service delivery and features while remaining responsive to customer needs and wants.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the time since, we have announced our largest client deployment of EEC to date, continued to optimize EEC through feature enhancements such as vCloud Director’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/blog/2019-04-04-deploy-kubernetes-clusters-alongside-virtual-machines-with-expedient-enterprise-cloud/&quot;&gt;Container Service Extension&lt;/a&gt; (CSE), and expanded our national footprint with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/about/media/expedient-enhances-national-service-offerings-with-recent-western-expansion/&quot;&gt;cloud points of delivery&lt;/a&gt; in the Western United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, a lot has happened at Expedient (and with EEC) in the last year, so we were happy that 451 Research decided to check in on Expedient and EEC in its latest Market Insight report: &lt;em&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud positioned as stepping stone from the old world to the new.&lt;/em&gt; Authored by the co-founder of 451 Research, William Fellows, the report emphasizes EEC’s competitive position to hyperscale cloud providers and focuses on the main differentiators of EEC, such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ability to run containerized workloads and VM-based workloads in the same cloud resource pool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robust, built-in security features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Per GB, term-based pricing based on consumption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expedient’s 100% Service Level Agreement (SLA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The report also provides an overview of the VMware cloud infrastructure components that comprise EEC as well as the architecture of each EEC cloud POD (point of delivery). Download the full report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/resources/451-research-eec-positioned-as-stepping-stone-between-old-world-and-new/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Chief Innovation Officer, John White is the lead executive at Expedient responsible for the company’s product and technology vision. In addition to leading Expedient’s product strategy function, John also serves as the lead technology evangelist for the company, works closely with the sales team on closing complex/high brand deals, and acts as Expedient’s primary interface with existing technology partners. Follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johna_white&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">Shortly after we announced Expedient Enterprise Cloud (EEC) at VMworld 2018, 451 Research published its initial Market Insight report on the groundbreaking cloud, which noted that:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--451_Stepping_Stone.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Game-changing Security Solutions Highlighted at Juniper Networks’ NXTWORK 2019</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-19-game-changing-security-solutions-highlighted-at-juniper-networks-nxtwork-2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Game-changing Security Solutions Highlighted at Juniper Networks’ NXTWORK 2019" /><published>2019-11-19T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-19T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/game-changing-security-solutions-highlighted-at-juniper-networks-nxtwork-2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-19-game-changing-security-solutions-highlighted-at-juniper-networks-nxtwork-2019/">&lt;p&gt;For a second consecutive year, I attended the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.juniper.net/us/en/dm/nxtwork-amer-2019/&quot;&gt;Juniper NXTWORK 2019&lt;/a&gt; conference in Las Vegas, NV, along with more than 1,000 other participants to discuss our business relationship with Juniper and learn about new technologies on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Becoming-a-Gamechanger-Juniper.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The convergence of security with the entire network infrastructure is a key focus of Juniper Networks’ forward-looking protection strategy. Partners and clients like Expedient that have made the transition to software-defined and next-generation services by embracing the Juniper ecosystem, are taking advantage of integrated solutions with a particular focus on cloud and software technologies. In doing so, we’re &lt;em&gt;changing the game&lt;/em&gt; by delivering integrated solutions that help clients meet the requirements of government and industry compliance mandates and prepare them for a multi-cloud future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This focus builds upon Juniper’s connected security platform with the goal of extending security to all points of connection on the network to safeguard all users, infrastructure, and endpoints. For example, Expedient offers a variety of managed security services built atop the vSRX virtual firewall platform, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/#UnifiedThr&quot;&gt;Unified Threat Management (UTM)&lt;/a&gt;, which enables content filtering and intrusion detection, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/#AdvancedTh&quot;&gt;Advanced Threat Prevention (ATP)&lt;/a&gt; to deliver next-generation protection against zero-day events through cloud-based malware detonation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Juniper strategy of extending security to every port involves building the functionality into its products such as EX and QFX switches, MX routers, and SRX firewalls. In the past, network threat detection has been limited to perimeter technologies like endpoint software and firewalls. Now, more integration along the path is possible to enable a truly threat-aware solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/NXTWORK-2019_Magic-Johnson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Earvin “Magic” Johnson&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Managed &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/#Distribute&quot;&gt;Distributed Denial of Service (DDOS) Protection&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/#VirtualPri&quot;&gt;Virtual Private Network (VPN) service&lt;/a&gt; additionally enable reliable and secure data transmission across public networks. Learn more about all of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/&quot;&gt;security and compliance solutions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aforementioned transition to services was reinforced at the conference through keynote addresses, including one in particular from the athlete, businessman, and philanthropist – Earvin “Magic” Johnson. He spoke about the importance of differentiation and teamwork to winning. He connected the event’s theme of becoming a “Game Changer” to his many successful sports experiences, business ventures, and charitable pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they do every year at NXTWORK, the Juniper education team offered extensive opportunities for Juniper Networks Certification Program (JNCP) achievement, including free testing for all associate, specialist, and professional-level exams, discounted expert-level lab exams, and savings on lab-based exams and written exams at future dates. Other educational sessions throughout the week included automation, multi-cloud, SD-WAN, and advanced network telemetry and monitoring topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juniper also used the opportunity at NXTWORK to highlight its &lt;a href=&quot;https://newsroom.juniper.net/press-releases/juniper-networks-announces-intent-acquire-mist-systems-bring-ai-it-delivering&quot;&gt;recent acquisition of Mist Systems&lt;/a&gt;, and describe how it is using their foundational artificial intelligence (AI) technology to evolve its enterprise networking products. While Mist’s initial products are focused on wireless networking, a capability that was previously missing from the company’s line-up, executives espoused AI as a technology that will significantly influence new and differentiated solutions across their products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Rami-Rahim_NXTWORK-2019.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Juniper Networks CEO, Rami Rahim, welcomes participants to NXTWORK 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NXTWORK 2019 afforded participants an opportunity to hear from Juniper Networks executives and networking experts as well as connect with other clients and partners about the evolving networking landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Senior Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, Jonathan Rosenson is responsible for overseeing organizational functions that drive growth at Expedient. Jon additionally acts as an external spokesperson conveying the Expedient story.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rosenson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow him&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonathan Rosenson</name></author><category term="Security and Compliance" /><summary type="html">For a second consecutive year, I attended the Juniper NXTWORK 2019 conference in Las Vegas, NV, along with more than 1,000 other participants to discuss our business relationship with Juniper and learn about new technologies on the horizon.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--Juniper_NXTWORK.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">With DRaaS, Continuous Availability Equals Competitive Advantage</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-13-with-draas-continuous-availability-equals-competitive-advantage/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="With DRaaS, Continuous Availability Equals Competitive Advantage" /><published>2019-11-13T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-13T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/with-draas-continuous-availability-equals-competitive-advantage</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-13-with-draas-continuous-availability-equals-competitive-advantage/">&lt;p&gt;When IT disaster strikes every moment counts. Because of this, disaster recovery as a service (DRaaS) solutions that automate total network failover and orchestrate application recovery will create a competitive advantage for your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/disaster-recovery/&quot;&gt;Push Button DR powered by Zerto&lt;/a&gt; is one such solution. As Expedient has offered DRaaS solutions to its clients since 2011, we were well aware that networking and DNS failover was one of the largest obstacles companies face during the disaster recovery process. While virtual replication software like Zerto makes failing over VMs very easy, the manual intervention required to reconfigure network components and DNS records at the failover site really slows down IT recovery. Add in the fact that DNS changes can take hours to propagate, and you could be looking at 6+ hour recovery times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For organizations that require near-real-time recovery to ensure the continuous availability of business-critical applications, this obviously isn’t going to work. To solve this pervasive DR challenge, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/about/media/2016-09-12-expedient-demonstrates-disaster-recovery-as-a-service-draas-for-enterprise-workloads-with-juniper-networks-and-451-research/&quot;&gt;Expedient product strategy engineers combined the functionality&lt;/a&gt; of Juniper vSRX (virtual firewall) with the replication capabilities of Zerto’s IT resilience platform to create Push Button DR powered by Zerto - a unique DR solution that eliminates the need to update DNS records during a failover event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a recent webinar with Zerto, Expedient solution architect, Brent Meadows, provided an overview of how Push Button DR achieves this outcome. Watch the replay of the presentation to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-full h-full sm:w-7/12 video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/0YTnTChpwio&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Disaster Recovery" /><summary type="html">When IT disaster strikes every moment counts. Because of this, disaster recovery as a service (DRaaS) solutions that automate total network failover and orchestrate application recovery will create a competitive advantage for your business.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--continuous_DRaaS-darker.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Reduce Cybersecurity Risk with a Secure-by-Default Enterprise Cloud</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-12-reduce-cybersecurity-risk-with-a-secure-by-default-enterprise-cloud/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reduce Cybersecurity Risk with a Secure-by-Default Enterprise Cloud" /><published>2019-11-12T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/reduce-cybersecurity-risk-with-a-secure-by-default-enterprise-cloud</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-12-reduce-cybersecurity-risk-with-a-secure-by-default-enterprise-cloud/">&lt;p&gt;Is your organization facing a server or data center hardware refresh in the next 18 months? If so, you may be considering purchasing replacement equipment to put in your primary internal data center or colocation facility. You may also be considering enterprise cloud infrastructure as an alternative. The most common reasons that organizations choose cloud may appeal to you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operating expense replaces capital expense –&lt;/strong&gt; The CFO likes the idea of predictable technology costs that do not trap capital that could otherwise serve the core business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pay as you grow –&lt;/strong&gt; Pay for only the resources you use as you use them. Changes in the business can be mapped to incremental changes in cloud resources and associated costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offload tactical IT work&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;–&lt;/strong&gt; Many organizations would rather their IT staff spend time on supporting end users, applications and business initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher availability –&lt;/strong&gt; The vast majority of cloud data centers have fully redundant power, cooling and staff to ensure the highest levels of uptime for your systems and applications.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Familiarity and Compatibility –&lt;/strong&gt; Enterprise cloud platforms deliver VMware, Windows and Linux systems on highly redundant hardware, which is often exactly what your internal IT staff and your IT service providers know how to support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security –&lt;/strong&gt; Organizations want to leverage expert security best practices to reduce the risk of an outage or a data breach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all the reasons above have merit, the majority of organizations we meet with are most concerned about &lt;strong&gt;how the cloud can improve their security posture and reduce organizational risk&lt;/strong&gt;. Why is this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cybersecurity-is-a-top-risk&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity is a top risk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most CEO surveys today rank cybersecurity threats as a top-five risk, regardless of industry type. CEOs care about data breaches and ransomware attacks because attacks have become so common, regardless of organizational size or IT staff expertise. CEOs know that a ransomware infection or a data breach can put the life of the organization at risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;security-best-practices-are-difficult-and-expensive-to-implement&quot;&gt;Security best practices are difficult and expensive to implement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal IT staff often struggles to maintain an up-to-date, standardized set of security best practices. Why? Keeping security systems running and updated with proper patches and policies is time-consuming, expensive, and difficult. New threats often require new tools or new security equipment. Few internal IT staffs can keep up with the ever-changing landscape of threats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-cloud-infrastructure-reduce-the-risk&quot;&gt;How can cloud infrastructure reduce the risk?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Infrastructure platforms like Expedient Enterprise Cloud (EEC) have best-in-class security features baked into the architecture, which enables a secure-by-default cloud experience. For instance, standard EEC security features include: Active Directory integration, micro-segmentation, data encryption at rest, multi-factor authentication (MFA), and role-based access control (RBAC). In other words, running your applications on a fully managed cloud platform like EEC can help you implement security best practices without having to evaluate security tools, purchase, license, implement, maintain, and update these tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, your internal IT staff needs only to work with the cloud infrastructure provider to understand the catalog of security features, then work with the provider to select and configure based on the organization’s security posture. Co-management of security tools by an enterprise cloud provider like Expedient will free up your IT staff to focus on strategic projects and will reduce the ever-present cybersecurity burden on your staff and IT environment. Just imagine, your IT staff can take PTO confidently knowing that security will be handled while they are away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-security-expectations-should-i-have-for-an-enterprise-cloud-provider&quot;&gt;What security expectations should I have for an enterprise cloud provider?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best enterprise cloud providers deliver these security best practices as a standard part of their offering:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiple firewalls&lt;/strong&gt; with automated threat management and protection – Firewalls define a secure perimeter to prevent access by bad actors and to alert you if someone tries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disk-based encryption at rest&lt;/strong&gt; – All company data is encrypted on cloud storage, making the data even more difficult to read, even in the event of a breach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-factor authentication (MFA) for administrators&lt;/strong&gt; – Like an ATM card with a PIN, MFA only allows Administrators to access systems if they have a physical security token plus a passcode.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network micro-segmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – Limiting which servers can talk to each other limits systems access by bad actors even if a breach were to occur.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging and optional log aggregation&lt;/strong&gt; of activity on computer systems with the ability to audit those logs allows forensic teams to evaluate what happened during a breach or an attempt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cant-i-do-the-same-thing-internally&quot;&gt;Can’t I do the same thing internally?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you can implement similar tools internally but the cost of implementing the best practices mentioned above and their associated tools can run upwards of tens of thousands of dollars per year once you factor in acquisition costs, support, maintenance, upgrades, troubleshooting and continuing education. Why not let the experts handle it so that you can focus on your business knowing that your IT infrastructure is secure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Interested in learning more about how Expedient Enterprise Cloud can increase your security posture while decreasing time-consuming security administration?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:doug.theis@expedient.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contact me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;for more information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Doug Theis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;is the Director of Market Strategy in Expedient’s Indianapolis market focused on engaging with and improving the regional IT community through planning, sponsoring and attending community events, facilitating IT-focused continuing education opportunities, and sharing strategies, tactics, and research to help IT professionals stay abreast of best practices and industry trends. Connect with Doug at&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:doug.theis@expedient.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;doug.theis@expedient.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/dougtheis&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Doug Theis</name></author><category term="Security and Compliance" /><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">Is your organization facing a server or data center hardware refresh in the next 18 months? If so, you may be considering purchasing replacement equipment to put in your primary internal data center or colocation facility. You may also be considering enterprise cloud infrastructure as an alternative. The most common reasons that organizations choose cloud may appeal to you:</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--cybersecurity-EEC.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Expedient Registers with Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) Assessment</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-07-expedient-registers-with-cloud-security-alliance-csa-assessment/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expedient Registers with Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) Assessment" /><published>2019-11-07T05:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-07T05:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/expedient-registers-with-cloud-security-alliance-csa-assessment</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-07-expedient-registers-with-cloud-security-alliance-csa-assessment/">&lt;p&gt;The Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) Security, Trust, Assurance and Risk (STAR) registry publicly increases trust among cloud service providers (CSPs). The CSA STAR Program encompasses key principles of transparency, rigorous auditing, and harmonization of standards. Expedient now demonstrates its adherence to security and privacy best practices through its &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/star/registry/expedient/&quot;&gt;registration with CSA STAR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CSPs registered with the CSA STAR Program annually complete the Consensus Assessments Initiative Questionnaire (CAIQ), which then becomes available to any organization seeking control alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (EEC) infrastructure as a service (IaaS) offers a single pane of glass management interface with self-service network provisioning, intuitive monitoring and analytics, and self-service multi-tenancy for computing management that enables a policy-driven approach ensuring control. The service is a scalable VMware software-defined data center (SDDC) offering operational consistency between on-premises workloads and the cloud offered in three models:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; – maximum cost effectiveness through shared infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; – maximum segmentation for challenging compliance requirements through dedicated infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Site Private Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; – an Expedient private cloud at any qualified location to meet data residency and latency requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clients choose the delivery model(s) most appropriate for their workloads and use the CAIQ to guide their own assessment of control alignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/data-centers/&quot;&gt;Expedient data centers&lt;/a&gt; support the Expedient Enterprise Cloud and a variety of complementary managed services. Partner data centers and client locations may also be used where applicable, making the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudsecurityalliance.org/star/registry/expedient/&quot;&gt;Expedient CSA STAR registration&lt;/a&gt; a valuable tool for assessing compliance and security posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expedient offers a variety of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/security-and-compliance/&quot;&gt;security and compliance services and attestations&lt;/a&gt; that complement clients’ own efforts to maintain compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Senior Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, Jonathan Rosenson is responsible for overseeing organizational functions that drive growth at Expedient. Jon additionally acts as an external spokesperson conveying the Expedient story.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rosenson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow him&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonathan Rosenson</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><category term="Security and Compliance" /><summary type="html">The Cloud Security Alliance (CSA) Security, Trust, Assurance and Risk (STAR) registry publicly increases trust among cloud service providers (CSPs). The CSA STAR Program encompasses key principles of transparency, rigorous auditing, and harmonization of standards. Expedient now demonstrates its adherence to security and privacy best practices through its registration with CSA STAR.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--CSA.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">IDC: Expedient Delivers Compelling Value to Customers with Enterprise Cloud Platform</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-01-idc-expedient-delivers-compelling-value-to-customers-with-enterprise-cloud-platform/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IDC: Expedient Delivers Compelling Value to Customers with Enterprise Cloud Platform" /><published>2019-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/idc-expedient-delivers-compelling-value-to-customers-with-enterprise-cloud-platform</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-11-01-idc-expedient-delivers-compelling-value-to-customers-with-enterprise-cloud-platform/">&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/resources/IDC-Whitepaper-Expedient-Delivers-Compelling-Value-to-Customers-with-Enterprise-Cloud-Platform/&quot;&gt;ExpertROI® Spotlight report&lt;/a&gt; by IDC provides a deep-dive analysis of the Expedient Enterprise Cloud (EEC) platform and explores the vision that Expedient shared with VMware to create a cloud services offering that enables businesses to leverage existing VMware investments and expertise. This shared vision and partnership created a unique cloud platform (EEC) that provides a much-needed alternative path to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With EEC, enterprises with legacy applications running on VMware infrastructure don’t have to endure the costly and inefficient re-platforming process required for optimal performance on public clouds like AWS, Microsoft Azure or Google Cloud Platform. By providing a managed cloud experience within the familiar confines of the VMware universe, Expedient has filled a sizeable gap in the cloud services marketplace according to the IDC Report.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes.com, a leading online real estate platform, is a case in point. To streamline its cloud operations and control costs, Homes.com consolidated all of its workloads on to the EEC platform. Watch Homes.com President, Dave Mele, discuss the business outcomes the company has realized since its migration EEC:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-full h-full sm:w-7/12 video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/194kjeuVZqg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong demand for EEC’s differentiated functionality has transformed Expedient’s business in the year since it was launched. John White, Expedient’s Chief Innovation Officer and the lead visionary behind EEC, said in the report:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“With companies understanding that a lift and shift to public cloud may not be feasible, whether it’s financial or from technical debt, that’s driving a lot of business our way, because our services are very differentiated. We’re one of the only companies in the market that has this VMware-based cloud offering, so we’re benefiting from being a first mover.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download a copy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/resources/IDC-Whitepaper-Expedient-Delivers-Compelling-Value-to-Customers-with-Enterprise-Cloud-Platform/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to read the full report.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">This ExpertROI® Spotlight report by IDC provides a deep-dive analysis of the Expedient Enterprise Cloud (EEC) platform and explores the vision that Expedient shared with VMware to create a cloud services offering that enables businesses to leverage existing VMware investments and expertise. This shared vision and partnership created a unique cloud platform (EEC) that provides a much-needed alternative path to the cloud.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--IDC_Report.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Trends in Cloud Native – What’s on the Horizon for Enterprise IT</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-31-trends-in-cloud-native-what-s-on-the-horizon-for-enterprise-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trends in Cloud Native – What’s on the Horizon for Enterprise IT" /><published>2019-10-31T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/trends-in-cloud-native-what-s-on-the-horizon-for-enterprise-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-31-trends-in-cloud-native-what-s-on-the-horizon-for-enterprise-it/">&lt;p&gt;Faster development, faster delivery, faster return… The value of cloud native approaches is indisputable in today’s always-on digital economy, but the path to successful implementation is unclear for businesses burdened with legacy IT environments and technical debt. As this challenge comes up frequently in conversations with clients and prospects, we decided to dig deeper into the subject with independent analyst firm &lt;a href=&quot;https://451research.com/&quot;&gt;451 Research&lt;/a&gt; in our recent webinar: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trends in Cloud Native – What’s on the Horizon for Enterprise IT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this webinar, 451 Research co-founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://451research.com/analyst-team/analyst/William+Fellows&quot;&gt;William Fellows&lt;/a&gt; and I discussed the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adoption of cloud native trends such as microservices, containers, Kubernetes, DevOps, and serverless computing (Functions as a Service or FaaS)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The impact and evolution of cloud native&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roadblocks that are hindering the implementation of cloud native technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (EEC) supports cloud native practices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two EEC case studies that illustrate the cloud native functionality of our platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watch the full replay of the webinar now:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;w-full h-full sm:w-7/12 video&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rvB-Lc2B5BQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Chief Innovation Officer, John White is responsible for Expedient’s product and technology vision. John also serves as the lead technology evangelist for the company, works closely with the sales team on complex engagements, and is Expedient’s primary contact for technology partners. Follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johna_white&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">Faster development, faster delivery, faster return… The value of cloud native approaches is indisputable in today’s always-on digital economy, but the path to successful implementation is unclear for businesses burdened with legacy IT environments and technical debt. As this challenge comes up frequently in conversations with clients and prospects, we decided to dig deeper into the subject with independent analyst firm 451 Research in our recent webinar: Trends in Cloud Native – What’s on the Horizon for Enterprise IT.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP_451_TrendsinCloudNative__1200x630.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Push Button DR: Resiliency Options for your Diverse Application Portfolio</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-30-push-button-dr-resiliency-options-for-your-diverse-application-portfolio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Push Button DR: Resiliency Options for your Diverse Application Portfolio" /><published>2019-10-30T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-30T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/push-button-dr-resiliency-options-for-your-diverse-application-portfolio</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-30-push-button-dr-resiliency-options-for-your-diverse-application-portfolio/">&lt;p&gt;We &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/about/media/2019-06-28-expedient-announces-expanded-draas-offerings-based-on-vmware-vcloud-availability/&quot;&gt;recently expanded&lt;/a&gt; our portfolio of disaster recovery as a service &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/disaster-recovery/&quot;&gt;(DRaaS) solutions&lt;/a&gt; to provide clients and prospects with more flexibility and choice when it comes to replication options for computing workloads. This diversified DRaaS approach is based on the reality that most organizations utilize myriad workloads that each require different levels of protection. Our multi-tiered approach also supports hybrid DR strategies by allowing clients to mix and match protection levels based on the needs of specific applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations with applications or workloads that cannot endure any downtime whatsoever should consider &lt;strong&gt;Push Button DR powered by Zerto&lt;/strong&gt;. This DRaaS solution offers rapid, total network failover at the push of a button, without IP or DNS changes. By automating this aspect of the disaster recovery process, Push Button DR powered by Zerto eliminates the time-intensive process required to manually configure network components after failover, enabling the near-real-time recovery that business-critical, enterprise workloads demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While all businesses have workloads that require total uptime, other workloads don’t require this level of total availability. Businesses can reduce DRaaS spend by protecting these non-business-critical workloads with a solution that achieves tolerable recovery time objectives (RPOs) and recovery point objectives (RTOs). To support hybrid disaster recovery strategies that seek to match protection levels with the uptime requirements of each application, Expedient recently added two new tiers of protection to its Push Button DR solution set:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push Button DR powered by VMware vCloud Availability (vCAV)&lt;/strong&gt; is perfect for VMware-based workloads that don’t require near-real-time RPOs. As Push Button DR powered by vCAV is a VMware-native solution, enterprises can be confident that their on-premises or hosted VMware workloads will continue to run consistently in the event of a failover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Push Button DR powered by Cohesity&lt;/strong&gt; offers snapshot-based replication and is perfect for protecting lower priority workloads already running on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/services/cloud/&quot;&gt;Expedient Enterprise Cloud&lt;/a&gt; (EEC). This protection tier based on the Cohesity Data Protection platform enables EEC clients to save money by addressing backups and disaster recovery with a single replication solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter the level of protection required, all clients will always enjoy the universal benefits of Push Button DR:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Industry-leading solution &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.expedient.com/magicquadrant2019&quot;&gt;positioned in Gartner’s Magic Quadrant for DRaaS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;White-glove delivery process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infrastructure DR Runbook Included&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unlimited self-service or supported DR tests included at no extra charge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24x7x365 support provided by Expedient’s technical experts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100% Service Level Agreement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/resources/push-button-dr-infographic/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download our Tiered Resiliency Infographic to learn more.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Chief Innovation Officer, John White is the lead executive at Expedient responsible for the company’s product and technology vision. In addition to leading Expedient’s product strategy function, John also serves as the lead technology evangelist for the company, works closely with the sales team on closing complex/high brand deals, and acts as Expedient’s primary interface with existing technology partners. Follow him on&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/johna_white&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>John White</name></author><category term="Disaster Recovery" /><summary type="html">We recently expanded our portfolio of disaster recovery as a service (DRaaS) solutions to provide clients and prospects with more flexibility and choice when it comes to replication options for computing workloads. This diversified DRaaS approach is based on the reality that most organizations utilize myriad workloads that each require different levels of protection. Our multi-tiered approach also supports hybrid DR strategies by allowing clients to mix and match protection levels based on the needs of specific applications.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--PushButtonDR-1.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Achieving TechQuilibrium at Gartner IT Symposium/XPo</title><link href="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-25-achieving-techquilibrium-at-gartner-it-symposium-xpo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Achieving TechQuilibrium at Gartner IT Symposium/XPo" /><published>2019-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-10-25T04:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/knowledgebase/blog/achieving-techquilibrium-at-gartner-it-symposium-xpo</id><content type="html" xml:base="/knowledgebase/blog/2019-10-25-achieving-techquilibrium-at-gartner-it-symposium-xpo/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com&quot;&gt;Gartner&lt;/a&gt; is a leading research and advisory company, equipping leaders and their teams in major business functions with the insights, advice and tools to achieve their mission-critical priorities today and tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;gartner-it-symposium--xpo-2019-highlights-the-breadth-of-advisory-services-the-company-offers&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Expedient_GartnerSymposium.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;center&gt;Gartner IT Symposium / XPo™ 2019 highlights the breadth of advisory services the company offers.&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gartner bills its IT Symposium/XPo™ 2019 as the world’s most important gathering of CIOs and IT executives, hosting more than 9,000 CIOs and senior leaders. IT Symposium/XPo™ brings together a community of IT leaders, technology visionaries and Gartner experts to examine critical industry trends to help organizations build and execute world-class IT strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended IT Symposium/XPo™ this year for the fourth time, and, over the course of several days, heard from some of more than 190 Gartner experts and 180 solution providers in several of the 450+ sessions spanning technology &amp;amp; information, leadership and business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;techquilibrium-key-to-digital-transformation-success&quot;&gt;TechQuilibrium Key to Digital Transformation Success&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year, Gartner introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.expedient.com/knowledgebase/blog/2018-10-19-is-your-organization-continuousnext/&quot;&gt;its concept of ContinuousNEXT&lt;/a&gt; – the idea that to confront and adapt to changes in technology, competition, and business, organizations must constantly develop new capabilities and create new ways to succeed. This year’s new concept is TechQuilibrium – the idea that every enterprise has a point that defines how digital they need to be to compete (or lead) in a digital society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2019-10-21-gartner-says-organizations-must-have-techquilibrium-to-win-in-the-turns&quot;&gt;his presentation this week&lt;/a&gt; on the topic, Gartner senior research vice president, Valentin Sribar, explained that three “turn” forces – geopolitics, economics, and the emergence of digital giants trigger shifts from the normal momentum of a business. Unique concepts like ContinuousNEXT and TechQuilibrium represent helpful labels to describe organizational capabilities that will differentiate an organization digitally. With these labels, Gartner tries to encapsulate multiple concepts in one term that they use as a platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keynotes-that-inspire-techquilibrium&quot;&gt;Keynotes That Inspire TechQuilibrium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;jennifer-hyman-at-gartner-it-symposium--xpo-2019&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Expedient_GartnerSymposium-Jennifer.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;center&gt;Jennifer Hyman at Gartner IT Symposium / XPo™ 2019.&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the three prior years that I’ve attended Gartner IT Symposium/XPo™, I’ve been impressed by the line-up of keynote speakers. This year was no exception with inspiring messages from the likes of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sir Tim Berners-Lee&lt;/strong&gt;, Inventor of the World Wide Web, including HTML and HTTP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Malcom Gladwell&lt;/strong&gt;, New York Times Best-Selling Author and Journalist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jennifer Hyman&lt;/strong&gt;, Co-Founder and Chief Executive Officer of Rent the Runway&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colin L. Powell&lt;/strong&gt;, Former U.S. Secretary of State and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sekou Andrews&lt;/strong&gt;, Award-winning Poetic Voice, Entrepreneur, and Two-time National Poetry Slam Champion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;general-colin-l-powell-at-gartner-it-symposium--xpo-2019&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/Expedient_GartnerSymposium-ColinLPowell.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;center&gt;General Colin L. Powell at Gartner IT Symposium / XPo™ 2019.&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of TechQuilibrium was present in each of these speakers’ discussions – in different ways. For example, Sir Tim Berners-Lee focused on balancing ethics and expectations in a digital world, while Colin Powell discussed persuasion and diplomacy’s place in technology’s integration in society. For his part, Malcom Gladwell shared how the timing of innovation is rarely correlated with immediate commercial success and suggested that learning, discovery, and normative familiarity play an important role in adoption and relevance. In the process, he taught me a new term: &lt;strong&gt;innovation lag&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard Sekou Andrews deliver an engaging poetic slam about disruption’s role in innovation using his own story of building a business based upon poetry, which some told him didn’t seem like a good idea. Finally, Jennifer Hyman told the audience that their client relationships aren’t based upon perfection – they deal with mistakes transparently and use them as learning opportunities to improve the experience. I identified with many of the points made by these speakers and learned some new ones as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tapping-trends-for-techquilibrium&quot;&gt;Tapping Trends for TechQuilibrium&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gartner Analyst Brian Burke announced the top 10 strategic technology trends for 2020 at the event. The trends are structured around the idea of “people-centric smart spaces,” which means considering how these technologies will affect people and the places in which they interact. The context of how and where technology will be used is critical to innovating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Hyperautomation&lt;/strong&gt; – the combination of machine learning, packaged software, and automation tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Multi-experience&lt;/strong&gt; – the shift in how users perceive and interact with digital assets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Democratization of Expertise&lt;/strong&gt; – access to business and technical domain expertise without requiring extensive and costly training&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Human Augmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – the exploration of how technology is used to deliver physical and cognitive improvements for better user experience&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Transparency &amp;amp; Traceability&lt;/strong&gt; – the critical elements to support privacy and digital ethics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;The Empowered Edge&lt;/strong&gt; – the rise of more complicated edge devices such as robots and autonomous vehicles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Distributed Cloud&lt;/strong&gt; – a significant shift from the centralized model of most current public cloud services that will lead to the next era of cloud computing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. &lt;strong&gt;Autonomous Things&lt;/strong&gt; – physical devices like drones and robots that use AI and automation to perform functions previously done by humans&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. &lt;strong&gt;Practical Blockchain&lt;/strong&gt; – every year adoption seems just out of reach, so will this be the year?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. &lt;strong&gt;Security Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt; – leverage AI to enhance security defense, while anticipating nefarious use of it by attackers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No single organization will adopt all these trends immediately, and some will be more relevant than others, but all of them are sure to become more prevalent as the velocity of digital transformation increases over time. More detail on these trends is available in this Gartner &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gartner.com/en/newsroom/press-releases/2019-10-21-gartner-identifies-the-top-10-strategic-technology-trends-for-2020&quot;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The measures of TechQuilibrium achievement will vary by organization, but this new Gartner label adds to the language they use to describe capabilities for digital transformation. For my part, I experienced an educational week at Gartner IT Symposium/XPo™ 2019 that involved attending nearly a dozen sessions about technology and process, as well as numerous personal meetings and analyst interactions. Talking with information technology professionals in a variety of industries provides context and validation about both the challenges and opportunities faced by the organizations we serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Senior Vice President and Chief Operating Officer, Jonathan Rosenson is responsible for overseeing organizational functions that drive growth at Expedient. Jon additionally acts as an external spokesperson conveying the Expedient story.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rosenson&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow him&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;on Twitter.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jonathan Rosenson</name></author><category term="Security and Compliance" /><category term="Cloud" /><summary type="html">Gartner is a leading research and advisory company, equipping leaders and their teams in major business functions with the insights, advice and tools to achieve their mission-critical priorities today and tomorrow.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/uploads/EXP-Social--Gartner-IT_Expo.png" /></entry></feed>